2048년
The year is 2048.
기술발전의 통제는
불가능하게 되었다
Evolving technologies
can no longer be regulated.
기술의 위험한 발전은
범죄의 지평을 바꾸어 놓았다
Dangerous advancements forever
alter the criminal landscape.
경찰들은 준비되지 않았다
Police are not prepared.
사법당국은
이러한 상황에
Law enforcement combats
this corruption
새로운 방어수단과 같이
전선에 서게되었다
with a new line of defense.
하지만 모든 수단이 동일한 것은 아니다
But not all are created equal.
DRN의 기초 아이디어는
가능한 인간다워지는거거든
The idea behind the DRNs
was to be as human as possible.
인조 영혼이라 불리는 프로그램에 기반해 있어
They were based on a program
called Synthetic Soul.
이건 그 미친 놈이잖아
That's one of the crazy ones.
- 제가 먼저 갈까요?
- 가자!
- I'll lead you in?
- Let's go.
이제 모든 경찰은
Now all cops...
인간과 기계가 함께
human and manmade together...
전투에 참여해
사회를 지키게 되었다
take on the battle
to watch over us all.
Almost Human S01E09
Unbound(풀려나다)
방영일자: 2014. 02. 03
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
다음엔 뭘 볼까요?
What do we want to see next?
좀 재밌는데는 없나?
How about somewhere
interesting?
소풍은 재밌어야지
Field trips are supposed
to be fun.
배우러 온거에요, 존
They're here to learn, John.
참 많은걸 배우고 있겠다
I'm sure they're
learning a lot.
자, 그럼
All right,
여기 착한 사람있나요?
which of you are the good guys?
신고전화를 어디서 받는지
알고싶은 사람?
Now, who wants to know
where the 911 calls go?
아니면...
Or...
총 보관한 곳 보고싶은 사람은?
who wants to see
where we keep the guns?
말도나도 경위님 만나고 싶은 사람?
Well, who wants
to meet Captain Maldonado?
아니면
Or who wants
나쁜놈들 어떻게 되는지 궁금한 사람?
to see what happens to bad guys?
그렇지
Yeah.
조니 호로위츠 기억나니?
You guys remember
Johnny Horowitz, right?
우리 조니씨는 결국
Well, old Johnny's luck
운이 바닥났었지
eventually ran out.
봐봐,
자기 범죄조직 사람들이
You see,
his organized crime pals,
이렇게 만들어놨어
they did this to him.
팔을 깔끔히 날렸지
Blew his arm clean off.
자
Okay.
다들, 저리 가자
You know what,
come on, let's go.
어디 가는거야?
Hey, where-where you going?
너무 갔어요, 존
You took it too far, John.
잠자리 적셔야지
Bed-wetters.
여기있어요
Here you go.
사랑스러운데요
They're lovely.
집에 가자마자
물에 넣으세요
Put them in water as soon
as you get home.
그럴게요, 고마워요
I will, thank you.
- 다음주에 봐요, 타냐
- 네
- See you next week, Tanya.
- Okay.
안녕
Bye.
지금 뭐 하는...
What do you think you're...
가져가요, 제발
Take it. Take it, please.
경찰이다. 멈춰
멈춰라
무기를 내려놔라!
Surrender your weapon!
스캔해 봐
No explosives,
no foreign objects.
폭발물 없음,
내부 시스템은 중지됐습니다
This is another service bot
범죄를 위해 개조된 서비스용 로봇입니다
reprogrammed to commit a felony.
Yeah, I get it, Sherlock.
알겠다. 셜록 탐정님
주위 통제하고,
사진찍고 증거 담아
Lock up the scene, photograph
and bag the evidence.
평소대로 해
Routine procedure.
Where's the file?
파일은?
Case number 45344.
사건번호 45344입니다
Make sure you tag it, too.
번호 꼭 붙여놔라
How did you get in here?
어떻게 들어온거야?
I've been in here
for a long time.
나 여기 오래 있었어
증거 보관실에서
바로 나갔습니다
It walked right to
that evidence crate
어딜 가는지 아는 것처럼요
like it knew where
it was going.
처럼이 아니라, 알았어
Not like. It did.
알아낸 건요?
What do you guys got?
22시 47분에 신고들어왔어
Call came in at 2247.
이 로봇이 총 들고 강도질하는걸
본 목격자가 여럿이야
Multiple witnesses saw this
bot mug a woman at gunpoint.
지갑을 건네주자
After she handed over her purse,
몸에 대고 쐈고
it shot her point blank.
경찰들이 쫓아서 파괴했지
Officers chased it
and destroyed it.
그런 줄 알았지
At least, they
thought they did.
이거 심각한 문제야
We have a huge problem here.
더 나은 각도 보여줄 수 있나?
Can you bring up
a better angle?
저 머리 아는 사람?
Anybody recognize that head?
말도 안돼
That's impossible.
그럴 수 없는데
It can't be.
- 확실합니까?
- 그래
- Are you sure?
- Positive.
XRN이야
It's an XRN.
증거 보관실에서 뭐하는 겁니까?
What's it doing
in our evidence locker?
죄송해요, 이해를 못하겠는데
I'm sorry, I don't follow.
XRN이 뭡니까?
What is an XRN?
- 우리가 파괴한 줄 알았지
- 뭘 파괴해요?
- I thought we destroyed it.
- Destroyed what?
몸은 파괴했어
The body was destroyed;
the head's been
머리는 2년동안
증거실에 있었고
in our evidence locker
for two years.
누군가 로봇이 범죄를 저지르도록
프로그램해서
So someone programmed a bot
to commit a crime,
우리 증거실에 보관하도록 했네요
get taken out, and end up
in our evidence locker
저 머리를 훔치려고요?
to steal that head?
그렇지.
우발적 범죄가 아냐
Exactly. This was
no random crime.
존, 14구역과
John, bring in Districts 14,
15, 18구역 불려
15 and 18.
모든 서에 경계령 보내고
Put BOLOs out to every
precinct in the city.
무인기 전부 확보해서
감시 시작하고
Consolidate all drone
and sat surveillance.
추가 경호인력과 경찰관들
I want extra
security and patrols
고위급인사 전부에게 붙여
at all high-value targets.
인신디케이트,
인신디케이트가
Insyndicate.
Insyndicate made a run
몇 달 전 증거보관실에
침입하려 했잖아요
on our evidence locker
a few months ago.
이게 그들이 찾던겁니다
I think this is what
they were after.
인신디케이트나 다른 조직이
왜 원할까요?
What would Insyndicate
or anyone else want with it?
XRN은 기록이 없는데요
I have no record of an XRN.
저만한 무기를 든 XRN은
테러라고 할 수밖에 없어
An XRN with that much firepower
is nothing short of terrorism.
The Wall.
벽
벽이 어쨌다고?
What about the Wall?
If this is about terrorism,
테러에 관한거면
I can't think
of a better target.
최상의 목표일텐데요
You think she would try
to create a breach
저게 우리랑 저 너머 사이에
통로를 만들려 한다고요?
between us and the other side?
충분한 화력은 가졌잖아
She's certainly got
enough firepower.
벽 감시 사령관에게 경고해
Alert the watch
commander at the Wall.
경계수위 높이라고 하고
Tell them to be extra vigilant.
거리에 나다니지 못하게 해
I want her off the street.
경위님, 도대체 뭔 일입니까?
Captain, what the hell
is going on?
도리안
Dorian,
저게 밖에 있는 한,
많은 사람들이 죽어갈거야
as long as she's out there, a
lot of people are gonna die.
안녕하쇼
Hello.
어디 갑니까?
Where are you going?
그 파일에서 뭘 찾던간에
Whatever you're looking for
in those files,
못 찾을거야
you won't find it.
- 대부분 편집됐거든
- 왜요?
- They're mostly redacted.
- Why?
경찰에겐 부끄러운 일이니까
Because it's an embarrassment
to the department.
그 날 무슨 일이 있었는데요, 존?
What happened that day, John?
단 하루가 아니었어
First of all, it
wasn't one day.
3일이었지
It was three.
루모코프라는 회사 들어봤나?
You heard of a company
called Lumocorp?
네, 제 제조사잖아요
Yes. They made me.
Well, then you know
경찰에 들어온 지 얼마 안되서
not long after
they were integrated
into the police force, the DRNs
DRN들이 오작동하기 시작했어
began to malfunction.
행동이 예측 불가능, 불규칙했고
Their behavior became
unpredictable, erratic.
어떤 DRN은 자살도 했지
Some of them even took
their own lives
자기가 본 걸 못 견딘거야
because they just couldn't cope
with what they saw.
그래서 전부 직위 해제한 후
So you were all decommissioned
복제로봇인 MX로 교체했지
and replaced by a
generic robot, the MXs.
루모코프의 납품이 취소되자
After Lumocorp's order
was canceled, overnight,
하룻밤 사이에
잘 나가던 기업이
they went from being one
of the most successful companies
나락에 빠졌지
in the world
to a complete failure.
그래서
So,
엄청난 빚과
아무도 원하지 않는
faced with a mountain of debt
and a bunch of androids
안드로이드를 가지고
that nobody wanted,
그 회사 사장은
새로운 로봇을 만들었어
the guy who ran the company
came up with a new bot.
XRN이지
The XRN.
경찰보다 병사에 가깝게 설계했고
He designed it to be
more soldier than cop,
시내 그린 가에서
화려한 시연회를 했지
and they had a big demo
for it downtown, Green Street.
정치인들도 왔었고,
권력가들은 다
All the politicians were
there, power players.
말하자면
Let's just say
it didn't go well.
잘 안됐어
내 부대가 둘째 날 파견됐을때는
By the time my unit was
called in on the second day,
건물밖에서 부상자 분류를 해야 했어
they'd set up a triage
outside the building.
의료진이 사상자 수를 못 따라가는거야
Medics couldn't keep up
with the casualties.
36시간동안
For 36 hours,
모든 무기를 가지고 공격했어
we assaulted it with
everything we had.
철갑탄,
Armor-piercing rounds,
광폭탄에 MX를 때려부었지
light bombs, waves of MXs.
경찰 26명이 들어갔는데
아무도 살아나오지 못했지
26 cops went into
...and never came out alive...
XRN이 몇 명이었는데요?
How many XRNs were there?
셋째 날에
On the third day,
꼭대기 층에서 코너에 몰아넣었어
we finally cornered her
up on the top floor.
파괴했지
We destroyed it.
남아있던건 머리밖에 없었어
The only thing that
was left was its head.
그 머리
That head.
Rudy, what have you got?
말도나도 경위님이 보내준 건
Captain Maldonado sent me
증거실에서 걸어나간 로봇이
what was left of the bot
that walked out
남기고 간거야
of your evidence locker.
좋은소식, 나쁜소식있어
I got good and bad news.
나쁜 소식은, 이 프로그램한 사람이
능력있다는거고
Bad news is, whoever
programmed it is talented.
얼마나?
How talented?
뭐, 몸 자체는
Well, the body was
기본적으로 구식 로봇이야
basically just an old scrap bot.
독특한 것도
추적할 만한 것도
There's nothing unique
or traceable
여기에는 없어
about the materials used,
그런데 개조는 천재적이야
but it's been ingeniously
modified.
개조?
Modified?
응. 숨겨진 두번째 동력원이 있었어
Yeah, it was designed with a
hidden secondary power source.
안드로이드를 가져온 경관들은
The officers that took
the android out thought
다 없앴다 생각했지만
they'd destroyed it,
증거실에 기록 올라가자마자
but once it was booked
into evidence,
대체 전력이 가동되었고
that alternate power
activated, and, well,
그 다음은 너도 알거야
we all know what happened next.
누가 이런걸 만들어 낼 수 있지?
Do you have any idea who could
create such a thing?
몰라, 전화하고
물어볼 수는 있어
Uh, I don't know. I could make
a few calls, ask around.
You said something
about good news.
좋은 소식도 있다며
Um, yeah, that burning
was nothing.
응. 쓰린건 별거 아니래
Uh, my test results
came back negative.
검사결과는 음성으로 나왔어
Wait... how do you know
about that?
잠깐.. 네가 어떻게 알아?
About the case, Rudy.
사건 말야. 루디
Yeah.
그래
아, 좋은 소식은
Ah, yes, the good news,
she may have
her own Achilles' heel.
이 로봇도
약점이 있을지 몰라
As I was saying, the materials
used to make the body
이 몸을 만든 재료들이
저급 부품들이고
are very crude,
and if it's running
2차 동력원으로 작동된다면
on a secondary power source,
멀리가진 못할거야
I'll wager
she won't get very far.
새 몸이 필요해
She'll need a new body.
Danica.
다니카
Attention, all units:
모든 대원은 주목한다
target sighted in Section 43,
warehouse district.
43구역에서 감시대상 목격,
창고 구역이다
Target has fled the scene.
대상은 현장을 빠져나갔다
피해자는 의식이 있으며
작은 상처만 났다
Victim is conscious,
minor lacerations.
케넥스 형사님
Detective Kennex.
고마워, 모리스
Thanks, Morris.
나이젤 버나드씨의 창고입니다
The warehouse is
owned by a Nigel Bernard.
여기 왔을때 로봇이 있었답니다
The bot was here
when he got home.
응급 의료요원이 보는 중입니다
EMTs are with him now.
몸을 바꾸러 왔나보군
Looks like it came
here to change bodies.
이 버나드는 뭐하는 사람이야?
What does this Bernard guy do?
좋은 질문이네요
That's a good question.
버나드 박사가 누구던
저 사람은 아녜요
Whoever Dr. Bernard
is, that's not him.
무슨 소리야?
What do you mean?
이 사람 알아?
Do you know this guy?
실례합니다
Excuse me.
아직도 경찰이군
You're still a police officer.
I am.
맞아요
도리안이라 부르죠
They call me Dorian.
그렇지, 그렇겠지
Yes, of course they do.
잠깐..?
May I?
생각지도 못했어//
I never thought that...
내가 모르는 것이 있나?
Is there something I'm missing?
아, 죄송합니다
Uh, forgive me.
아침부터 놀랄 일이 많네요
It's been quite a morning
for surprises.
존 케넥스 형사님,
나이젠 본 박사세요
Detective John Kennex,
this is Dr. Nigel Vaughn.
절 만드셨죠
He created me.
나이젤 본이라구요?
You're Nigel Vaughn?
나이젤 본 박사,
루모코프의 창립자요?
Dr. Nigel Vaughn,
founder of Lumocorp?
아쉽지만, 오래전 일이네요
Regrettably, I'm a very long way
from those days.
이름을 바꾸셨네요
You changed your name.
그랬지
어떻게 아직 있는거야?
Yes, I-I did.
How are you still on the force?
복귀했어요
I was recommissioned.
- 너 하나니?
- 네
- Are you the only one?
- Yes.
정말 그리웠단다, 도리안
I've missed you
so much, Dorian.
저기
Hey.
본 박사님,
뭘 요구하던가요?
Dr. Vaughn, what did
it want from you?
다니카
Danica.
다니카?
Danica?
- 제 프로토타입, 그렇게 부르죠
- 네
- My prototype. That's what
I called her. - Right.
그래서, 뭘 요구했습니까?
So, uh, what did it want
from you?
제 연구실로 데려가 달라더군요
She wanted me
to take her to my lab.
이제는 연구실이 없다고 얘기했죠
I told her I no longer have
a real lab.
로봇 다루는 자격증을
취소당했으니까요
I lost my license
to practice robotics.
잘 받아들이지 못하더군요
She didn't take that very well.
그런데
You know, for a guy
로봇 자격증 없는 사람치고는
who doesn't have
a license in robotics,
여기 로봇이 꽤 많은데요
you kind of got
a lot of robotics here.
그냥 수리 좀 하고
I just repair things now
될 때마다 옛 부품 팝니다
and I sell old parts
whenever I can.
먹고 살아야 하잖습니까
형사님
I mean, we all have
to eat, Detective.
왜 연구실을 쓴다고 했죠?
Why would she want to use your lab?
- 모르겠네요
- 이름도 바꿨고
- I don't know.
- You changed your name. You've...
드러나지 않으시려고
노력하셨네요
gone to extraordinary lengths
to keep a low profile,
그런데 당신을 찾으려
누군가 그 머리를 프로그램했구요
but somebody programmed
Danica's head to find you.
누군지 아십니까?
- Do you have any idea who? - I've made a lot
of enemies since my botched demonstration
그 망한 시연회 이후 적이 많아져서
on Green Street,
Detective. I'm...
- 상상되시겠죠
- 그 중에 침입한것 같은
- sure you can well imagine. - Any
of them capable of building an android
안드로이드를 만들 수 있는 사람은요?
like the one that broke
into our evidence locker?
- 모르겠네
- 본 박사님
- I don't know.
- Dr. Vaughn...
Please, call me Nigel.
나이젤이라 불러
Nigel, do you have any idea
where she's going?
나이젤, 그 로봇이 어디로 가는지는 아십니까?
필요한 것이나 원하는 것은요?
What she might need or want?
아뇨, 난..
No. No, I...
이건 2년 전에 겪었던 일들인데
You know, I went through
all of this two years ago.
그때도 뭘 원하는지 몰랐죠
I don't know
what she wanted then,
지금도 모르겠습니다
and I don't know
what she wants now.
다니카는 제 경력에서
최대의 실수죠
Danica was the greatest mistake
of my career,
인생에서도요
of my life.
그 책임은 제가 집니다
I take responsibility for that,
그런데 탈출은 제 실수가 아닙니다
but it's not my fault
that she got out.
형사님이 이게 어떤지는 아십니까
I don't know if you know what
it's like to be part of something
원하지도 않는 식으로
that defines you forever
and in a way
평생 생각되면서 사는 것 말이오
that you do not
wish to be defined.
쉽지 않아요.
어딜 가던, 사람들이 보고, 알고
It's not easy. Everywhere I
went, people looked. They knew.
내 이름을 들었으니 알겠지
They heard my name, they knew.
"그 살인 로봇을 만든 사람이다
"There goes that guy that
made that killer robot,
그 많은 사람들을 죽인 기계말야"
that machine that
murdered all those people."
죄송합니다
I'm sorry.
시간 내주셔서 감사합니다
Well, thank you for your time.
도움될 만한 것이 떠오르시면
If you can think of
anything that'll help us
전화주십시오
in our investigation,
please give me a call.
- 감사합니다
- 나이젤, 어려운 건 알지만
- Thanks again. - Nigel, I
know this is hard for you.
과거가 우릴 결정짓진 않아요
It's not our past
that defines us.
지금 뭘 하느냐가 중요하죠
It's what we do now.
만약에 제가..
There is a chance...
아주 약간이라도
a very small chance,
옛 기기들을 다룰 수 있으면
that if I had some
of my old equipment back,
추적할 수 있을지 모릅니다
I might be able to trace her.
루디에게 본 박사 데려갑니다
We're taking Vaughn and Rudy.
이게 될까, 존?
You think it'll work, John?
다른 방법이 없지 않습니까
Look, we don't have a choice.
I need you to get
본 박사 실험장비
사용명령 받아주십쇼
a release order
for Dr. Vaughn's lab equipment.
경찰 죽이는 안드로이드가
I've got a cop-killing android
내 도시에서 설치고 다니는데
뭘 원하는지도
at large in my city,
with no clue what it wants
어디있는지도 모르는데
실험장비가 니 답이야?
or where to find it, and
your answer is lab equipment?
- 본 박사가 추적가능합니다
- 내 '생각엔'
- Vaughn says he can track it.
- Oh, whoa, I said I think
- 할 수 있을거라고
- 할 수 있답니다
- I can track her. - He
thinks he can track it.
- 사건 파일 찾았습니다
- 신속반출명령 내려
- I got the case files.
- Get an order to release it.
Fast. We're on it.
해결 중이다
누구세요?
Who are you?
Wow. Well, whose temple is this?
와우, 여긴 누구 성전이신가?
Mine... Y-Your Highness.
접니다.. 폐하
Uh, Dr. Rudolph Lom,
루돌프 롬 박사입니다
- at your service.
- Um,
- 맘대로 부리세요
- 음
I'm Nigel. Um, you may,
나이젤이요. 음,
일어나시죠
uh, rise.
You've been such an inspiration.
당신은 정말 영감을 주시는 분입니다
Th-The DRNs are simply
amazing, Well...
DRN은 정말 대단해요
the greatest robotic, uh,
achievement of our generation,
최고의 로봇기술이죠
우리 세대의 업적이랄까요
uh, in my humble opinion.
제, 우매한 소견으로는요
Well, um, thank you, Rudolph,
for saying that.
고마워요, 루돌프
그렇게 말해줘서
Watching you work even
from afar was like
멀찍이서 당신의 작품을 보는 것은
glimpsing Michelangelo
at the peak of his talents.
미켈란젤로의 능력을 훔쳐보는 것과
같았습니다
Your hands are instruments
당신의 손은
혁신의 도구이며,
동상으로 만들어야 해요
of innovation. They should be...
they should be bronzed.
제가 봐도 될까요?
Do you mind if I see them?
Uh...
죄송합니다. 난...
Sorry. I...
I don't mean to gush.
그러려던 건 아닌데
I'm just a big fan.
엄청난 팬이에요
Uh, thank you. I should have you
talk to my ex-wife.
고마워요, 내 전부인과 자네가
이야길 했어야 했군
Oh, I'd be happy
to give her a call.
아, 전화드리면 제 영광입니다
- It would be an honor...
- I was... joking.
- 정말 영광스럽게..
- 농담한건데
아, 저도요
Oh, yeah. So am I.
잠깐.. 얘기 좀 나누느라
We were... sharing a moment.
여기서 뭘 찾는겁니까, 박사님?
So what are
we looking for here, Doc?
음, 은색 케이스에
Ah. A, um,
silver case,
10-68이라 써져있을겁니다
and it'll be marked 10-68.
The contents may...
다니카를 찾을지도 모르죠
찾을'지도'요
give us the ability to track
Danica, and I emphasize "may."
찾고 나면 어떻게 합니까?
After we find her, what then?
바라는 바는
평화적으로 작동을 정지시켜
Well, hopefully, we'll be able
to shut her down peacefully
더 이상 살육이 없도록 해야죠
and avoid any further bloodshed.
엄청난 가정이네요
That's a pretty big "if."
네, 그런것 같네요
Yes, I suppose it is.
뭐 찾은 것 같은데요
I think I
found something.
그래? 봐도 될까?
Yes? May I see?
이게 뭔가요?
What are these?
내 최대 업적이지
My greatest achievement.
It's what makes you
너를 너답게 만드는 거야
you.
Synthetic souls.
인조 영혼
- 당신 탓이군요
- 아뇨
So you're to blame.
No,
형사님, 제가 다른 걸로
Detective, I can be blamed
비난 받을 수는 있어도
for many horrible things,
인조 영혼은 거기 포함 안됩니다
but synthetic souls are not one
of those horrible things.
어디서 영감받으셨는지
May I ask what was
물어봐도 될까요?
your inspiration?
Ah.
형체없는 것을 잡아내려고 했죠
Well, I was trying
to capture the intangible.
당신도 알다시피
Y-You understand, of course,
DNA는 현미경 아래서
격리시킬수 있잖소
that DNA can be isolated under
a microscope. Uh, you know,
머리 색이나, 눈 색, 키
hair color, eye color, height,
몸무게, 인종도..
weight, ethnicity...
the fundamental
개인 염색체까지 추적가능한
기본 정보들 말이요
basic data can be traced
to individual chromosomes.
하지만 영혼은...
But the soul...
이게 인간이죠
That is who we are.
That is our passion.
우리 열정이고
Our pain.
아픔이고
It's why we laugh, why we cry,
왜 울고 웃는지
why we strive to be better.
왜 더 나아지려 안달하는지
DNA, it's
DNA는
the-the data, but the soul...
그냥 정보지만, 영혼은..
that's the story.
이야기를 담죠
That is the essence of life.
생명의 정수지
생명을 만들고 싶었소
I wanted to create life.
뭐가..
What did you do...
다른거죠?
differently?
그 로봇의
With her
인조 영혼은요?
synthetic soul?
이것만 기억해
넌 걔랑 다르다
Just remember something:
you are not like her.
알겠어?
Okay?
그러니까,
청사진은 같지만..
I mean, the blueprint
is the same, but...
어떻게 확신해요?
How can you be sure?
몇 가지는
Some things
다르게 했어야 하는데
I really wish
I'd have done differently.
케넥습니다
Kennex.
나야
It's me.
뭔일이래?
What's up?
시내 중심가에 기술회산데
I'm at a, uh, tech company
in the downtown core.
너희 로봇이 휩쓸고 간 것 같다
Looks like your girl
came in swinging.
실험실 조수로 벽을 칠해놨어
She painted the walls
with a lab assistant,
다른 직원들을 엄청 죽여대고
and she massacred
a bunch of other employees
무균실 들어간다고
just to get into the clean room.
거기 뭐가 있는데?
What did it want in there?
훔친건 500개의...
She stole 500, uh...
ZNA 처리 코어?
"ZNA processing cores"?
그게 뭐야?
What are they?
내가 알겠냐
Like I know.
알았어. 고맙다
Okay. Thanks.
당신 로봇이 방금
Your robot just broke into
시내 회사에 침입해서
사람들을 죽이고
a company downtown,
killed a bunch of people,
ZNA 처리 코어를 훔쳤습니다
and stole some
ZNA processing cores.
생각나는 거 있으신가요?
That mean anything to you?
그것들은..
처리 장친데요
Well, I mean, they're...
they're processors.
안드로이드면 다 있는겁니다
Every android has one.
그건 고급용이네요
But those are very advanced.
그것들로는
I mean, they're capable
병렬 계산으로
초당 10²¹ 부동소수점연산이 가능합니다
of a zeta-flop
of parallel computations
per second.
나는 그게 뭔지 모르지만...
I don't know
what that means, but, um...
500개를 훔쳤답니다
she stole 500 of them.
- 왜 500개죠?
- 단순 계산인데
- Why 500?
- Simple math.
안드로이드 하나 당 칩 하나니까
One chip per android.
그 처리 코어로는
With those processing cores,
다니카 500개를 만들어 낼 수 있죠
you'd be well on your way
to conceivably making
500 Danicas.
누군가 안드로이드를 만드는군요
Someone's building androids.
- 손님이 왔어
- 아, 손님 좋죠
- You have a visitor. - Great.
I love visitors.
큰 기술회사에서
He works in robotics
로봇을 다룬대.
루디가 불렀어
for some big tech company.
Rudy called him.
혹시라도 그 사람이
Thought he might
have some insight
누가 살인 로봇을 풀었는지 알 수도 있을까 해서
into whoever put this homicidal
robot back onto the street.
본 박사는 어떻게 됐어?
Where are you at
with Dr. Vaughn?
루디씨랑 같이
추적 소프트웨어 만드는 중입니다
He and Rudy are working on
the tracking software now.
다니카를 추적하려면
They need a little
bit more time
- 시간이 필요하대요
- 다니카?
- to attempt to locate Danica.
- Danica?
프랑켄슈타인 박사가 붙인 이름입니다
That's what Dr. Frankenstein
called it.
귀엽네
Cute.
케넥스 형사입니다
I'm Detective Kennex.
제 파트너 도리안이구요
This is my partner, Dorian.
- 루터 에스테스입니다
- 저희는 지금
Luther Estes.
We're investigating
로봇 관련 배경을 가진
용의자를 찾고있습니다
a suspect with
a robotics background.
저희가 범인 특성을 찾는데
도와주실 수 있다구요
Dr. Lom said that you may be
able to help us build a profile.
이건 일반적인 업무 로봇이 아닙니다
This isn't a normal worker bot.
최신 설계에요
These are cutting-edge designs.
여기있는 구상 몇 가지는
Some of these concepts are just
로봇 관련 최고 대학들에서 이제 이론화 된겁니다
being theorized
in the top robotic universities
in the world.
팔라듐 외피로 회로를 만들었군요
This bot has
palladium-encrusted circuits.
엄청 비싼데다
희귀하기까지 한데
They're hugely expensive
and extremely rare.
기술은 조악해요
But the work is raw.
주류세계에 있는 사람은 아니죠
Someone who's not
beholden to conventions.
아마 어릴겁니다
Probably younger.
이런 기술을 가진 사람을 아십니까?
Do you have any idea who might
be capable of this kind of work?
뉴 도쿄에 히카리가 있긴한데
There's a kid
in New Tokyo... Hikari.
이런 작업 가능할거에요
She'd be capable
of work like this.
이 근처 사람이라면,
제가 들어본 적이 있을텐데요
If it were someone local, I'd
have heard about them by now.
벽 너머에 있는 사람은 어떤가요?
What about someone
on the other side of the Wall?
로봇이 저 너머에서 왔을 가능성도
We have to consider
the possibility that
고려해야 하거든요
the bot came from over there.
그건 농담이죠?
What is that, a joke?
이런 재료는 어디서 얻겠어요?
Where would they
get the resources?
이런 머리를 가진 사람이면
Anyone this intelligent
would not still be on that side
벽 너머에 있겠어요?
of the Wall.
자발적으론 안남아요
Not willingly, anyway.
Here it is... it's our
best shot at finding Danica.
여깄습니다.
다니카를 찾는 최선의 방법이겠죠
이 안에는
Well, inside of this...
독특한 특징이 있습니다
is a unique signature,
다니카에 맞춰진 에너지죠
an energy specific to Danica.
그 특징만 걸러내면
Once we isolate that signature,
경찰 추적 시스템에 올려서
we can upload it
into your department's
이론적으로는
tracking system and,
theoretically,
찾아낼 수 있습니다.
네트워크의 MX, 안드로이드를
be able to track her, just
as you would any MX or android
찾는 방식으로요
on your network.
당신이 만든 것을
잘 모르시는 것 같습니다
I don't think you understand
what you created.
- 네?
- 도리안요
Pardon?
With Dorian.
당신의 목표는
Your goal was to design androids
경찰에 투입될 로봇을
설계하는 것이었지만
to integrate
into the police force,
그 이상을 만들어 내셨어요
but you created
so much more than that.
네, 세상은 그렇게 진화한 기계를
Yes, well, I'm afraid the world
wasn't ready for a machine
받아들이지 못했네요
quite so evolved.
재판 기억납니다
I remember your trial.
정말 유감이었어요
I felt badly for you.
그런 분 얼마 없는데
You were in the minority,
I'm afraid.
인조 영혼은 시대를 앞서간 거였어요
The Synthetic Soul program
was ahead of its time.
저는 그렇게 경계를 뚫고 갈
I don't know if
I'd have had the courage
용기가 있을지 모르겠네요
to push boundaries like you did.
당신 그 조심성이
Perhaps your caution
아직도 연구실에서
일할 수 있게 하는겁니다
is why you still have
a lab and I don't.
DRN은 인생의 역작이었죠
The DRNs were my life's work.
아이도 없었고
Don't have any children.
제가 그들에게 느낀 감정이
The love I felt for them...
아버지와 다르지 않았죠
was not unlike a father's.
그리고 오작동이 시작됐을땐
And when they started
to malfunction,
권력가들이 조용히
the powers that be
quietly decided
뒷방에서
in some back room that...
논리연산에 기반한
MX들이..
the logic-based
MXs were...
더 낫다고 결정했죠
the better way to go.
고칠 수 있는 기회도 없었소
Didn't even give me an
opportunity to try and fix them.
제가 MX와 매일 일하는데
말씀드리자면
Uh, I work with MXs every day,
and let me tell you,
저건 한계가 있어요
they have their limitations.
그러니까 저것들은 눈을 부릅뜨고 그냥 보고만 있어요
I mean, for a start, they
just stare at you with those...
beady eyes.
보세요.. 반응도 안해요
Look... they
don't even respond.
죄송해요, 말씀하시던거..
Sorry, you were saying?
뭐, 저는..
Well, I had a...
DRN 2차 부대가 다 만들어졌는데
a second fleet of DRNs
already built,
배치될 준비도 끝났었죠.
계약을 파기할 시점에요
ready to be deployed,
when they pulled my contract.
그리고 엄청난 빚이 생겼구요
Then I was crushed
under a mountain of debt,
전부 잃었죠..
회사며..
lost everything...
my company...
명성이며..
my reputation.
뭔갈 해야했어요
Had to do something.
그래서 XRN을 만들었어요?
Is that why you created her?
Mm-hmm.
뭘 할 수 있는지 아십니까?
Did you know what
she was capable of?
아뇨, 전혀 예상 못했죠
No, I didn't predict
any of this.
아무것도요
None of it.
그래도..
Although...
제가 DRN을 만들때는
you know, when I made
the DRNs, I was filled
일에 대한 열정과
with a passion for my work
희망으로 가득했었죠
and hope for where
we were going.
다니카를 만들때는
When I made Danica...
분노와 절박함 뿐이었어요
I was filled with resentment...
desperation.
가끔은 그 당시
I sometimes wonder if,
back then, something
내 안의 어두운 뭔가가..
that was dark inside of me...
거기 들어간건가..하죠
got put in... her.
우리 자신은
I mean, we are...
창조물에 대한 필수적 요소잖아요
an integral part of our
creations, aren't we?
하지만, 다니카는
But, you know, Danica is...
복잡해요
is complex.
그냥 흑백, 선악이 아니죠
Not just black and white
or good and evil.
세상은 단 한 면만을 봤고
The world only saw
one part of her, and that,
그게 그거였죠
as they say, was that,
and I've been prevented
저는 그 후부터 로봇기술을
쓸 수가 없구요
from practicing robotics
ever since.
에너지 특징을
You captured
잡아내셨군요
her energy signature.
작동하는지 보죠
Let's go see if this works.
4번가, 캐스퍼로 교차로요
Take us to 4th
and Caspar, now.
- 택시 영업 안해요
- 불이 켜있잖아요
This cab is off duty.
Your light was on.
미터기도 켜있고
4번가랑
And your meter's still on.
Take us to 4th
캐스퍼로 교차로, 당장
and Caspar now.
영업 안한다구요
I just said I'm off duty.
언니 참 예쁜거 같아요
I think you're very pretty.
가자, 아가
Let's go, honey.
XRN주파수를
Just got to install
her frequency
추적 소프트웨어에
설치하면 돼
onto our tracking software.
왜 이러지?
What's wrong with this?
이유는 모르는데
안 서네
I don't know why
I can't get it up.
XRN말야... 신호가 안 서
I mean with her. I mean...
with her signal.
난 잘 서고.
거기에는 문제 없어
I can get it up.
I have no problem
in that department whatsoever.
I'm just... that's not...
이런거는
얘기하기 적당한 건 아니겠네
really an appropriate thing
to be talking about
긴급상황인데
in the middle of an emergency
형사님앞에서..
with... you guys.
나는.. 이거나 할게
I'll, uh... I'll
just keep working on this.
본 박사님, 또 필요한 거 있으신가요?
Dr. Vaughn, is there anything
else that you require?
저리 가게
Go away.
그건 또 뭡니까?
What the hell is that?
EMP 대못이지
An EMP spike.
전자기 펄스를
If we set the
electromagnetic pulse
XRN주파수에 맞추면,
무력화할 수 있을거야
to her frequency, we
should be able to disable her.
나온다, 되네
That's her. It worked.
수고했어요, 본 박사님
어디야?
Well done, Dr. Vaughn.
Where is she? Find out
저기 뭐 있는지 알아봐, 스탈
- what's in that area, Stahl. - She's
moving towards the northwest corner
3번가와 메인로의 북서쪽으로 가는데요
차량 이동 중입니다
of 3rd and Main.
She's in a vehicle.
- 대부분 상점이나 음식점인데요
- 기술을 훔치는거면
- Looks like mostly retail and restaurants.
- If this is about
왜 저기 간거야?
stealing tech, why is she there?
신호 추적하고 무인기 보내
Track her signal
and send drones.
- 박사님?
- 잘들어요, 삽입하려면
- Doc? - Yeah, now, listen,
you need to get close enough
최대한 가까이 가야해요
to insert that.
It has to go
정확히 두개골 뒤에 꽃혀야 합니다
precisely into
the back of her skull.
두개골 뒤요?
The back of her skull?
지금 살인 로봇한테 걸어가서
You're telling me to walk up
to a homicidal robot
목 뒤를 찌르라는 겁니까?
and stab it in the back
of the neck?
Uh-huh.
죽이네
Great.
가능한 MX는 다 데리고 가
Take as many available
MXs as you need.
잘 하셨어요
Great work.
도리안?
Uh, Dorian?
조심하게
Be careful.
목표_스캔_중
목표_확인
제임스 하트 - 시 의원
- 얼마나 걸리지?
- 2분 안에 도착해요
- How far out are we?
- Less than two minutes.
바에 들어갔어요
3번가 2723번지
She just went into a bar.
2720 3rd Street.
전화번호 찾아서
건물에서 대피시켜
Pull up the phone number.
Start evacuating the building.
바에서 뭐하는거야?
What the hell is
she doing in a bar?
방금 사무실에 연락했는데
I just spoke to the
bar's corporate office.
제임스 하트 시의원
재선 기금 모금 행사래요
They're holding a reelection
fund-raiser for Councilman James Hart.
손님 명단을 보냈는데
They forwarded over
the guest list...
권력가들은 다 들어있습니다
it's a who's who of the
city's power players.
리스트 상호 조사해서
Cross-reference the list...
see if anybody
로봇 관련된 사람 있나 봐
has any ties to robotics.
하고 있습니다
I'm on it.
안녕하세요
Um... hi.
명단에 있으신가요?
Are you on the list?
- 룩손 바입니다, 어떻게 도와드릴까요?
- 경찰입니다. 지금 당장
- Bar Luxon. Can I help you?
- This is the police. We need you
건물 밖으로 대피...
to evacuate
the building as soon...
여보세요?
Hello?
총 소리에요
Shots fired.
총성이 나고 있습니다
We're hearing shots fired now.
폴이 지원부대 데리고
가는 중이야
Paul's on his way
with reinforcements.
케넥스 형사님
Officer Kennex.
건물은 1층에
동쪽, 서쪽 입구가 있습니다
The building has east and west
access on the first floor.
Take a team
in the west entrance.
서쪽 입구로 가
우회로가 필요한데
I need a diversion.
뒤 편에 화재비상구가 있습니다
There's a fire escape
around the back.
거기로 사람들 대피시킬게요
I'll evacuate people from there.
가자, 따라와!
Let's go, come with me!
가자!
Move!
영상통신이 전부 끊겼어!
We've lost all visuals!
존, 무슨 일이야?
John, what's happening?
고슨, 헤르난데즈 총에 맞았습니다
Gorson is down.
Hernandez is down.
We lost five MXs.
MX 5기도 잃었습니다
세상에
Oh, my God.
- 괜찮아요?
- 또 이러는 건가요?
- You okay?
- This is happening again?
박사님 탓이 아녜요
It's not your fault.
본 박사님, 회의실에서 기다리시죠
Dr. Vaughn,
maybe you should wait
in the conference room.
허? 네
Huh? Yes.
이거 되야 하는데
This better work.
EMP 안먹히잖아!
The E.M.P. didn't work!
본 박사 불러와!
Get Dr. Vaughn!
어디갔어?
Where'd he go?
왜 이러는거야?
Why are you doing this?
내 희생이 필요하니까
Because my sacrifice
is necessary.
너처럼 말이야
Just like yours.
우린 전혀 달라
We're nothing alike.
Dorian!
본 박사 건물에 없습니다!
Dr. Vaughn's not
in the building!
- 뭐?
- 사라졌어요
- What?
- He's gone.
정보가 없어,
아무것도 안보인다고!
We have no feed.
I cannot see anything!
뭐가 웃겨?
What's so funny?
네 수류탄 핀 뽑았거든
I got the pin to your grenade.
괜찮아?
You okay?
형사님은요?
You?
Ah...
나아지겠지
I'll be better.
인간 다리보다 낫죠?
Better than a human leg, huh?
아직도 인조 반대하세요?
Still anti-synthetic?
맘에 들어가고 있어
It's growing on me.
케넥스입니다
Kennex.
존?
John?
괜찮아?
Are you okay?
네, 괜찮습니다
Yeah, we're fine.
로봇은 파괴했습니다
Bot's destroyed.
본 박사에게 끝났다고 전해요
Tell Dr. Vaughn it's over.
본 박사 없어졌어
Dr. Vaughn is gone.
없어져요?
Gone?
- 어디로요?
- 모르지
Gone where?
We don't know.
경위님?
문제가 있습니다
Captain?
We have a problem.
DRN을 MX로 바꾸는 것을 지지합니다
I fully endorse replacing
the DRNs with MX androids.
왜 하트의원을 목표로 했는지
알 것 같습니다
I think I know why they're
targeting Councilman Hart.
위험한 로봇을 폐기하고
Need to be lost
before we decommission
these dangerous bots and end
this failed experiment?
실패한 실험을 끝내야 합니다
존, 이건 전부 오해라니까
John, I'm telling
you, this is all a mistake.
잘못 안거야
나이젤씨가 그럴리가
You've got it wrong,
Nigel wouldn't do this.
그래? 그럼 인조 영혼 가져와봐
Yeah? Then show me
those damn synthetic souls.
저기 놓는거 봤어
여기 있다고
I saw him put them away.
They're right here.
- 어디?
- 없어졌네
Where?
They're gone.
가자
Drive.
DRN이 오작동했을 때
When the DRNs malfunctioned,
하트가 계약취소의 뒤에 있었어요
Hart was the force
behind the recall.
루모코프사와의
DRN 계약취소에 투표하고
He voted to take away the city's
DRN contract from Lumocorp
and awarded the new MX contract
MX계약을 본 박사 경쟁자에게 줬죠
to Vaughn's competitor.
It was one last "screw you"
to his competitors
경쟁자에게
마지막으로 엿을 먹었군
사라지기 전에 말야
before he disappeared.
시의원은 머시 병원에서 회복중입니다
The councilman's recovering
at Mercy General.
혹시나 해서
개인 경호원 배치했습니다
I put a personal security
detail on him, just in case.
- 시의원을 노린게 아녜요
- 네, 하트의원은 보너스였죠
- This wasn't about Councilman Hart.
- Yeah, Hart was just a bonus.
재료를 얻고 싶었던 거지
This was about resources.
본 박사는 소규모 처리장치와
Vaughn wanted
the microprocessors
인조 영혼이 필요했던 겁니다
and the synthetic souls.
경위님, 7, 8구역에는
Captain, there are
no sightings of Vaughn
본 박사 목격담이 없습니다.
경계령 내렸고
in District 7 or 8.
We put out BOLOs
무인기는
공항, 모노레일
and assigned drones to the
airport, the monorail lines,
항구에 배치했습니다
and the ports.
도시를 빠져나갈 수 있는 곳은 모두요
Any conceivable place he'd
think to exit the city from.
그냥 사라진 거 아니니까
계속 찾아봐
But he didn't just disappear,
so keep looking.
어떻게 하고있나?
How's he handling this?
자기 창조자 만난것도
엄청날텐데
Must be a hell of a
thing to meet your maker.
배신당한다는건..
But to be betrayed by him...
괜찮아?
You okay?
연구실에서 뭔갈 말했어요
He told me something
in the lab.
뭐?
What?
박사한테 물었거든요
I asked him what
he did differently
다니카와 내 인조영혼의
차이가 뭐냐고
with Danica's synthetic
soul than he did with mine.
없대요
He said "nothing."
오작동이 났어요
She malfunctioned.
그 사람들을 죽였다고요, 존
She killed all
those people, John.
너도 그럴까봐 두려워?
You're afraid that's
gonna happen to you?
걜 만든 사람이 절 만들었잖아요?
How could the same man
that made her make me?
- 그런 짓을 했는데, 저도..
- 도리안
- If she's capable of all
those things, I... - Dorian.
넌 XRN과 달라
You're not like her.
박사와도 다르고
And you're not like him.
넌 너야
You're you.
그건 변하지 않는거야
And nothing's
going to change that.
본이 XRN을 만들땐 다른 상황이었어
Vaughn was in a different space
when he made her.
절망적이었잖아
He was desperate.
회사, 명성, 연구실
모든 걸 잃었었다고
He was losing his company, his
reputation, his lab, everything.
뭐?
What?
연구실요
His lab.
본은 군대를 만들만큼
로봇 기술을 훔쳤어요
Vaughn stole enough robotics
to build an army, man.
그냥 숨거나 사라지려는게 아녜요
He doesn't want to
hide away or disappear,
일을 하려는거지
he wants to work.
새 연구실이 필요하겠군
He needs a new lab.
- 경위님
- 응?
- Captain.
- Yeah?
본은 도망치는 게 아닙니다
보호 구역이 필요하죠
Vaughn's not looking to run.
He needs a sanctuary.
일을 할 수 있는 장소요
충분히 커서
A place where he can work.
Someplace big enough
로봇을 만들 수 있는 곳이요
for that kind of manufacturing,
전력 선에는 안나오는
off the power grid.
옛 항구에 버려진 조선소가 있어
The abandoned shipyards
at the Old Port,
거기부터 시작할 수 있겠네
that might be a place to start.
무너진 지하철 터널은요?
What about the subway tunnels
that collapsed during
광폭탄 공격 당한 곳요
지하이니까
the light bomb attack?
It's subterranean,
무인기 감시망도 벗어나요
it's out of sight of the drones.
벽 너머는요?
What about over the Wall?
정말 숨고싶다면
If you really didn't
want to be found...
어디서든 벗어나려면
to disappear off every grid...
거기로 가도 되잖아요
that would be the place to go.
본이 미치긴 했어도
I mean, Vaughn's crazy, but...
그정도는 아니지
not that crazy.
존이 맞아
I think John's right.
벽을 넘진 않았을거야
I don't think he'd
go over the Wall.
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com